<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Andrea Amelio</title>
    <link>https://aamelio.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Andrea Amelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aamelio.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bayesian updating</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/more/bayesian_updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/more/bayesian_updating/</guid>
      <description>a short post about Bayesian updating</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post-truth &amp; co.</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/more/post_truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/more/post_truth/</guid>
      <description>a collection of resources on post-truth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>other</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/more/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/more/other/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivated Memory in Economics - A Review</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/publications/memory_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/publications/memory_review/</guid>
      <description>Motivated reasoning refers to the idea that people hold certain beliefs about themselves or the world due to their desire to do so, rather than striving for accuracy. This type of belief formation can lead to overconfidence and polarization, as well as facilitate immoral behavior at both the individual and collective levels. One of the supply-side mechanisms for motivated reasoning is motivated memory, or the selective retrieval of past experiences or information based on self-serving criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Stories</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/jmp/tailored_stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/jmp/tailored_stories/</guid>
      <description>I study the problem of persuading a boundedly rational agent without controlling or knowing the piece of information she observes. Persuasion occurs by providing models whereby the persuader can communicate ways of interpreting observable signals. The key assumption is that the agent adopts the model that best fits what is observed, given her initial beliefs, and takes the action that maximizes her expected utility under the adopted model. I characterize the extent of belief manipulability in this setting and show that the agent may hold inconsistent beliefs across signal realizations &amp;mdash; posterior beliefs across realizations do not average to the prior &amp;mdash; because each signal may trigger the adoption of a different model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  Social Learning, Behavioral Biases and Group Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/0sl_metacogn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/research/0sl_metacogn/</guid>
      <description>In many relevant decision contexts we are affected by a wide array of behavioral biases. Likewise, we often have the chance to observe others&amp;rsquo; decisions and, possibly, change ours. This paper investigates the impact of social learning on a broad selection of behavioral biases, reflecting economically relevant decision-making frameworks. Through an online experiment, I document how social learning may amplify errors stemming from behavioral biases and lead to worse group outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Cognitive Uncertainty and Overconfidence</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/1cogunc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/research/1cogunc/</guid>
      <description>Overconfidence is one of the most ubiquitous cognitive bias. There is copious evidence of overconfidence being relevant in a diverse set of economic domains. In this paper, we relate the recent concept of cognitive uncertainty with overconfidence. Cognitive uncertainty represents a decision maker&amp;rsquo;s uncertainty about her action optimality. We present a simple model of overconfidence based on the concept of cognitive uncertainty. The model relates the concepts theoretically and generates testable predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Information Be Too Much? Information Source Selection and Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/2toomuchinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/research/2toomuchinfo/</guid>
      <description>Agents undertaking economic decisions are exposed to an ever-increasing amount of information sources, especially nowadays in what has been defined as the Information Age. This paper investigates how the number of available information sources impacts agents’ ability to (i) select reliable sources and (ii) use their content effectively to update their beliefs. To answer these questions, I set up an online experiment based on an automata model of decision-making and belief updating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contigent Belief Updating</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/3contigent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/research/3contigent/</guid>
      <description>We study the effect of contingent thinking on belief updating. One possible explanation for biased beliefs is that agents distort the underlying data generating process when updating their beliefs given a new piece of information. Engaging in contingent thinking — that is, reasoning through all possible contingencies without knowing which is realized — might affect the agents’ understanding of the data generating process, resulting in differences in belief updating. Through a series of online experiments, we aim to uncover and break down the effect of contingent thinking on belief distortions into two components: (1) hypothetical thinking (updating on a piece of not-yet-observed information) and (2) contrast reasoning (comparing multiple contingencies during the updating task).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
