<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Andrea Amelio</title>
    <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Andrea Amelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aamelio.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Cognitive Uncertainty and Overconfidence</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/2_cogunc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/research/2_cogunc/</guid>
      <description>Overconfidence is one of the most ubiquitous cognitive bias. There is copious evidence of overconfidence being relevant in a diverse set of economic domains. In this paper, we relate the recent concept of cognitive uncertainty with overconfidence. Cognitive uncertainty represents a decision maker&amp;rsquo;s uncertainty about her action optimality. We present a simple model of overconfidence based on the concept of cognitive uncertainty. The model relates the concepts theoretically and generates testable predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Information Be Too Much? Information Source Selection and Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/1_toomuchinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/research/1_toomuchinfo/</guid>
      <description>Agents undertaking economic decisions are exposed to an ever-increasing amount of information sources, especially nowadays in what has been defined as the Information Age. This paper investigates how the number of available information sources impacts agents’ ability to (i) select reliable sources and (ii) use their content effectively to update their beliefs. To answer these questions, I set up an online experiment informed by a simple automata decision-making and belief-updating model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contigent Belief Updating</title>
      <link>https://aamelio.github.io/research/0_contigent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aamelio.github.io/research/0_contigent/</guid>
      <description>We study how contingent thinking – that is, reasoning through all possible contingencies without knowing which is realized – affects belief updating. According to the Bayesian benchmark, beliefs updated after exposure to new information should be equivalent to beliefs assessed for the contingency of receiving such information. Using an experiment, we decompose the effect of contingent thinking on belief updating into two components: (1) hypothetical thinking (updating on a piece of not-yet-observed information) and (2) contrast reasoning (comparing multiple contingencies during the updating process).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
